whitepages.com.au 2003-12-10

# whitepages.com.au

|   
---  
Copyright  
Disclaimer  
Trade Marks  
Whereis™  
Map Service  
Postcode Disclaimer  
Privacy Statement  
Collection Statement  
|   
|  |   
|  |  | 

Updated December 2001. 

This statement should be read together with the Sensis Collection Statement. 

This web site is one of many sites owned and operated by Sensis Pty Ltd, a company that is committed to protecting the privacy of Internet users. Whilst our company strives to deliver more convenient, customised services that meet your present and future needs, Sensis also appreciates the uncertainty that comes with interacting in a constantly changing environment. We are sensitive to the concerns that our users may have with regards to the confidentiality, security and use of their personal information via our web sites, and would like to reassure you of our position on this matter. 

Sensis Pty Ltd encourages you to check the Sensis Pty Ltd privacy statement regularly as this privacy statement may change from time to time. If you have any suggestions or concerns that are not addressed in this privacy statement, please contact us. 

Please take some time to read through this statement and understand our position on privacy, by clicking the links: 

  * Our commitment to your privacy
    * Statutory and non-statutory requirements
    * Sensis Pty Ltd's Privacy Principles
  * What web sites does this statement apply to?
  * How is my personal information collected?
    * Cookies
    * Online forms
  * How can I control my personal information?
  * How secure is my personal information?
  * How is my personal information used?
  * Are my children at risk using web sites operated by Sensis Pty Ltd?
  * Third Party Sites
  * What else should I know about privacy?

---  
Our commitment to privacy  
Aside from the contents of this statement, Sensis Pty Ltd's conduct in the online environment is also governed by a number of statutory and non-statutory policies as part of the telecommunications industry, and our corporate privacy principles.   
Statutory and non-statutory requirements  
Sensis Pty is part of the Telecommunications Industry and as such, is governed by: 

  1. The Telecommunications Act 1997 (Cth) and industry codes; 
  2. The National Privacy Principles contained in Schedule 3 of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth); 
  3. Various current and proposed privacy regimes; 
  4. Laws and codes regulating and protecting Internet content; and 
  5. Some non-statutory industry codes such as the Australian Direct Marketing Association (ADMA) code of practice. 

Sensis also has its own policies and procedures designed to ensure that personal information is protected.   
  
Sensis Pty Ltd's Privacy Principles  
Sensis Pty Ltd operates in accordance with the following corporate privacy principles: 

**_Principle 1:_ Collection of information**  
Sensis collects personal information in a number of ways, including: 

  * directly from you, when you provide information by phone or in documents such as an application form; 
  * from third parties such as our related companies, carriage service providers, credit reporting agencies or your representatives; 
  * from publicly available sources of information; 
  * from the organisations identified below under "When we disclose your personal information"; 
  * from our own records of how you use our services; or 
  * when legally required to do so. 

**_Principle 2:_ Use of information**  
Your personal information may be used in order to: 

  * provide the services you require, including directory services, through a number of media; 
  * administer and manage those services, including charging, billing and collecting debts; 
  * inform you of ways the services provided to you could be improved; 
  * conduct appropriate checks for credit-worthiness and for fraud; 
  * research and develop our services; 
  * gain an understanding of your information and communication needs in order for us to provide you with a better service; 
  * maintain and develop our business systems and infrastructure, including testing and upgrading of these systems; 

Your personal information is also collected to promote and market other services which we consider may be of interest to you. If you do not wish us to contact you regarding other services please call 1800 039 059. 

**_Principle 3:_ Disclosure of information**  
For the purposes set out above we may disclose your personal information to organisations outside Sensis. The organisations to which we disclose information include: 

  * Telstra Corporation and other related companies; 
  * outsourced service providers who manage the services we provide to you, including: 
    * customer enquiries; 
    * mailing systems; 
    * billing and debt-recovery functions; 
    * information technology services; 
    * marketing, telemarketing and door-knocking services; 
    * market research; 
  * your representatives (eg your authorised representatives or legal advisers); 
  * credit-reporting and fraud-checking agencies; 
  * credit providers for credit related purposes such as creditworthiness, credit rating, credit provision and financing; 
  * our professional advisers, including our accountants, auditors and lawyers; 
  * government and regulatory authorities and other organisations, as required or authorised by law; 
  * organisations involved in: 
    * a transfer/sale of all or part of our assets or business (including accounts and trade receivables); and 
    * managing our corporate risk and funding functions (eg securitisation). 
  * other telecommunication and information service providers. 

**_Principle 4:_ Data quality**  
Prior to the use and disclosure of personal information, reasonable steps will be taken to ensure that personal information is relevant and to the extent necessary, accurate, complete and up to date for the purpose for which it is to be used. 

**_Principle 5:_ Data security**  
Safeguards will be maintained to protect personal information against unauthorised access, alteration, destruction, use or disclosure and against accidental loss. 

**_Principle 6:_ Openness**  
Sensis will have clearly expressed policies on its management of personal information and these will continue to be readily available. Sensis will take reasonable steps to let individuals know, generally, what sort of personal information it holds, for what purposes, and how it collects, uses, and discloses that information. 

**_Principle 7:_ Access and correction**  
Where Sensis holds personal information about an individual, it will provide the individual with access to the information on request, in a form or manner suitable to the individual's reasonable needs, except to the extent that: 

  * providing access would pose a serious and imminent threat to the life or health of any individual; or 
  * providing access would have an unreasonable impact upon the privacy of other individuals; or 
  * the request for access is frivolous or vexatious; or 
  * the information relates to existing legal dispute resolution proceedings between Sensis and the individual, and the information would not be accessible by the process of discovery in those proceedings; or 
  * providing access would reveal the intentions of Sensis in relation to negotiations with the individual in such a way as to prejudice those negotiations; or 
  * providing access would be unlawful; or 
  * denying access is specifically authorised by law; or 
  * providing access would be likely to prejudice an investigation of possible unlawful activity; or 
  * providing access would be likely to prejudice: 
    * the prevention, detection, investigation, prosecution or punishment of 
      * criminal offences; or 
      * breaches of a law imposing a penalty or sanction 
    * the enforcement of laws relating to the confiscation of the proceeds of crime; 
    * the protection of the public revenue; 
    * the prevention, detection, investigation or remedying of Seriously Improper Conduct; or 
    * preparation for, or conduct of, proceedings before any court or tribunal, or implementation of its orders; by or on behalf of an enforcement agency; or 
  * ASIO, ASIS or an enforcement agency performing a lawful national security function asks Sensis not to provide access on the basis that providing access would be likely to cause damage to the national security of Australia.  

Where providing access would reveal evaluative information generated within Sensis in connection with a commercially sensitive decision-making process, Sensis may give the individual an explanation for the decision, rather than direct access to the information. 

If Sensis has given an individual such an explanation and the individual believes that direct access to the evaluative information is necessary to provide a reasonable explanation of the reasons for the decision, Sensis will, at the request of the individual, undertake a review of the decision. The review will be undertaken by personnel other than the original decision maker. 

Wherever direct access by the individual is impractical or inappropriate, Sensis and the individual should consider whether the use of mutually agreed intermediaries would allow sufficient access to meet the needs of both parties. 

If Sensis levies charges for providing access to personal information, those charges: 

  * will not be excessive; and 
  * will not apply to lodging a request for access. 

If Sensis holds personal information about an individual and the individual is able to establish that the information is not accurate, complete and up-to-date, Sensis will take reasonable steps to correct the information so that it is accurate, complete and up-to-date. 

If the individual and Sensis disagree about whether the information is accurate, complete and up-to-date, and the individual asks Sensis to associate with the information a statement claiming that the information is not accurate, complete or up-to-date, Sensis will take reasonable steps to do so. Sensis will provide reasons for denial of access or correction. 

**_Principle 8:_ Identifiers**  
Sensis will not adopt as its own identifier an identifier that has been assigned by a government agency (or by an agent of, or contractor to, a government agency acting in its capacity as agent or contractor). Sensis will not use or disclose an identifier assigned to an individual by a government agency except where paragraphs (c) to (f) of Principle 3 apply. 

**_Principle 9:_ Anonymity**  
Whenever it is lawful and practicable, individuals will have the option of not identifying themselves when dealing with Sensis. 

**_Principle 10:_ Transborder data flows**  
Sensis will not transfer personal data outside Australia unless:  

  * Sensis reasonably believes that the recipient of the information is subject to a statute, binding scheme or contract which effectively upholds principles for fair information handling that are substantially similar to these rules; or 
  * the individual concerned consents to the transfer; or 
  * the transfer is necessary for the performance of a contract between the individual concerned and Sensis, or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures taken in respect to the individual's request; or 
  * the transfer is necessary for the conclusion or performance of a contract concluded in the interest of the individual concerned between Sensis and a third party; or 
  * the transfer is for the benefit of the individual concerned; and 
    * it is not practicable to obtain the consent of the subject of the information to that transfer; and 
    * if it were practicable to obtain such consent, the subject of the information would give it; or 
  * Sensis has taken reasonable steps to ensure that the information which it has transferred will not be collected, held, used or disclosed by the recipient of the information inconsistently with these rules. 

**_Principle 11:_ Sensitive information**  
Sensis will not collect personal information revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, or details of health, disability or sexual activity or orientation unless: 

  * the subject of the information has consented; or  

  * the collection is required or specifically authorised by law; or  

  * the collection is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to the life or health of any individual, where the subject of the information is physically or legally incapable of giving consent; or 
  * the collection is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim.  

**_Principle 12:_ New services and development**  
Sensis will consider the privacy impact of new services before they are introduced. 

Where appropriate, customers will be permitted to choose between various degrees of privacy protection in respect of these new services. 

**_Principle 13:_ Compliance audit**  
Sensis may maintain an independent compliance audit program to ensure its privacy protection principles and policies remain appropriate, and that Sensis operates in compliance with those principles and policies.   
  
What web sites does this statement apply to?  
This privacy statement applies to the web sites which are owned and operated by Sensis Pty Ltd (ACN 007 423 921) under the following domain names: 

* This also includes all Yellow Pages® _OnLine_ Branded web sites. 

In addition to those listed above, this statement may also apply to services offered by Sensis Pty Ltd on websites hosted by third parties. If so, express reference to this privacy statement must be made on those websites. As the _Sensis Pty Ltd_ , Yellow Pages® _OnLine_ , White Pages® _OnLine_ , Goeureka™ _Search_ and Whereis™ _OnLine_ web sites evolve, Sensis Pty Ltd will continue to update this privacy statement.   
  
How is my personal information collected?  
The types of personal information that we collect from you will depend on how you interact with Sensis Pty Ltd's web sites. This section will explain in a broad sense, the type of personal information that can be collected via our web sites, and how this information contributes to the development of Sensis Pty Ltd web sites. At the bottom of this section you can link to a page for a more specific description of what information is collected on each of our web sites and how it may be used.   
Cookies  
Many of the web sites owned and operated by Sensis use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website can transfer to an individual's computer hard drive for tracking (site usage) user navigation and customising site information to further improve the user experience. Cookies can make using Sensis Pty Ltd's websites easier, for example by storing information about your preferences on a particular website. This will enable you to take full advantage of the services that Sensis Pty Ltd and its affiliate sites offer. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you'll find most major websites use them. 

Most Internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies. However, if you are concerned about the use of cookies you do have the option to opt-out and refuse the transfer of cookies to your computer's hard drive. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your Internet browser to refuse cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. If you need further assistance to modify the cookie arrangement on your PC, please contact the company that produces your browser.   
  
Online forms  
When applying for membership or submitting information on some of our sites, we will collect details such as your name, email address and some details of your personal interests. Some of this information is essential for us to be able to identify accurately who is using the service so that we may be able to respond to your requests and, as such, is indicated by mandatory fields. Mandatory information requirements are clearly identified and are denoted by a red asterisks (*). You will also be prompted when submitting a form if mandatory data has not been completed. Other types of information, such as your age and gender, are collected to help us profile who is using the services and what their interests are. Information of this type is optional - you need only fill it in if you wish to do so. 

In general, you may be asked to provide Sensis Pty Ltd with personally identifiable information when you: 

  * Send us your comments or suggestions 
  * Report a technical problem 
  * Create a link to one of Sensis Pty Ltd's sites 
  * Register with a site 
  * Update your listing details 
  * Request sales and advertising information 
  * Volunteer to test Sensis Pty Ltd's products 

We value your trust in our web sites and, in all cases, your information will be held in the strictest confidence. For extra protection we have processes in place, so that whenever a page is requested from our web site, we record the time, date and URL of the request, along with information on the browser software that is being used. 

In all cases, the primary purpose in gathering information on our web site users is to gain a better understanding of your needs and wants, and develop new and innovative solutions. 

For specific information on what information is collected on Sensis Pty Ltds' web sites, click the links below: 

Yellow Pages® _OnLine_  
GOeureka™ Search  
White Pages® _OnLine_  
Whereis™ _OnLine_  

How can I control my personal information?  
Users are not required to register on Sensis Pty Ltd's web sites in order to use them. In certain cases registration will provide more information and enhance the user experience. This registration is an option only and will not restrict you from using other aspects of the site. 

Our commitment is to provide you with the opportunity to 'opt-out', access or correct any information you have submitted online to Sensis Pty Ltd or any one of its affiliate sites. Please refer to the appropriate site and page to request your changes. When notified and requested, Sensis Pty Ltd will remove any personal identifiable information from the current operational systems.   
  
How secure is my information?  
Any personal information that you submit to our web sites is held with the strictest confidence. Sensis Pty Ltd uses and implements industry standards for the security and protection of information collected from its users. This information is securely stored and access is restricted to authorised Sensis personnel only, ensuring that your personal information is protected and safeguarded (Sensis Pty Ltd Privacy Protection Principles; Principle 5: Data Security). 

The information you submit to Sensis Pty Ltd is used only for the purpose stipulated at the time that the information is collected. Sensis Pty Ltd is required by law not to reveal, disclose, sell, distribute, rent, licence, share or pass on to any third parties, any personal information that you may have provided to us unless we have your express consent to do so. 

Exceptions to this include: 

  * Where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health; and; 
  * Where Sensis Pty Ltd is required to provide information in response to Subpoenas or Warrants or other legal process, including requests from the Australian Stock Exchange. 

How we use information?  
The information we gather from your use of Sensis Pty Ltd and its affiliate sites enables us to provide better services that are tailored to your needs. Recording usage patterns help us identify the areas of our site that are popular and those that are not. The data that is gathered is aggregated for analysis by Sensis Pty Ltd. Identifiable characteristics are removed and the user remains anonymous. 

We use the information that you submit via an OnLine Form from any of the Sensis Pty Ltd web sites in any one of the following ways: 

  * To make changes to your profile at your request 
  * To register information at your request 
  * To respond to your submission or inquiry 

We will only record your e-mail address if you send us a message. It will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it, as outlined above. Your personal identifiable information will not be used for any other purpose, and we will not disclose it without your consent. 

The information and feedback you provide is used to identify ways of improving the sites and how we can make it more effective for your use.   
  
Are my children at risk using Sensis Pty Ltd's web sites?  
The safety of children is very important to us. 

We ask that children under the age of 16 have a parent or guardian verify their registration on web sites and the submission of OnLine Forms. Whilst Sensis Pty Ltd and its affiliated sites will make every reasonable effort to ensure that children's privacy and other rights are not compromised, it is ultimately the responsibility of parents or guardians to monitor their children's Internet usage. 

Children should always ask a parent before sending any transmission over the Internet.   
  
Third Party Sites  
  
Sensis Pty Ltd acknowledges that you will click-through to third party sites from our sites, and thus recommends that you refer to the privacy statement of the sites you visit. Sensis Pty Ltd's privacy statement is applicable for Sensis Pty Ltd and its affiliate sites (listed in full above), and assumes no responsibility for information and content of third party sites.   
  
What else should you know about privacy?  
Here are some more pointers to assist you in further protecting you privacy on the Internet. 

Remember to close your browser when you have finished your user session. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. You, as an individual, are responsible for the security of and access to your own computer. 

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information over the Internet (for example: in discussion forums, via email or in chat sites) that this information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information in publicly accessible online fora you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your username and passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are using the Internet and Sensis Pty Ltd or any of its affiliated sites.
